<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bitcoin.org Site Blog</title>
    <description>News about Bitcoin.org</description>
    <link>//</link>
    <atom:link href="//en/rss/blog.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 23:11:51 +0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 23:11:51 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v1.3.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>New Bitcoin Core Sub-Site</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin.org is proud to announce the addition of a dozen new pages to
the site about &lt;a href=&quot;/en/bitcoin-core/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Core&lt;/a&gt;.  Several of the pages describe &lt;a href=&quot;/en/bitcoin-core/features/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin
Core’s powerful features&lt;/a&gt;, others &lt;a href=&quot;/en/bitcoin-core/help&quot;&gt;provide help&lt;/a&gt; for Bitcoin Core
users, and several make it easier to &lt;a href=&quot;/en/bitcoin-core/contribute/&quot;&gt;start contributing&lt;/a&gt; to
Bitcoin Core.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/free/bitcoin-core-pages-collage.png&quot; alt=&quot;Excerpts from Bitcoin.org&#39;s Bitcoin Core pages&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Excepts from Bitcoin.org’s &lt;a href=&quot;/en/bitcoin-core/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Core&lt;/a&gt; pages&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both Bitcoin Core and Bitcoin.org have come a long way since the site
began promoting the earliest public versions of the software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/free/bitcoin-org-2009-03-03.png&quot; alt=&quot;Bitcoin.org homepage, 3 March 2009&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bitcoin.org homepage, 3 March 2009 (&lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20090303195936/http://bitcoin.org/&quot;&gt;Internet Archive&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These new pages give us a chance to introduce more recent Bitcoin users
to the advantages of full nodes like Bitcoin Core, particularly how full
validation &lt;a href=&quot;/en/bitcoin-core/features/validation#help-protect-decentralization&quot;&gt;helps protect Bitcoin’s essential decentralization&lt;/a&gt; from
takeover by a handful of miners, Bitcoin banks, and service providers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-brief-guide-to-the-new-pages&quot;&gt;A Brief Guide to The New Pages&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/en/bitcoin-core/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Core overview&lt;/a&gt;: provides a brief description of Bitcoin
Core and links to the other sections of the sub-site.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/en/bitcoin-core/features/&quot;&gt;Feature overview&lt;/a&gt;: briefly describes some of Bitcoin Core’s
leading benefits and links to pages that provide more details.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/en/bitcoin-core/help&quot;&gt;Get help page&lt;/a&gt;: resources to help Bitcoin Core users find help.
Prior to this PR, we also created and filled a category on the Bitcoin
Wiki with all the existing &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.bitcoin.it/wiki/Category:Bitcoin_Core_documentation&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Core help pages&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/en/bitcoin-core/contribute/&quot;&gt;Contribute overview&lt;/a&gt;: links to ways you can directly contribute to
Bitcoin Core and Bitcoin Core users.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;future-plans&quot;&gt;Future Plans&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We plan to enhance this new section of the Bitcoin.org website by
collecting together some of Bitcoin Core’s disparate documentation and
providing instructions for important ways users can enhance their privacy and
security while using Bitcoin Core—such as using Tor and an offline
wallet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, we hope to provide more resources that help businesses
understand the benefits of validating the transactions they receive with
their own full nodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to help, please feel free to email the Bitcoin.org
documentation maintainer,
&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:dave@dtrt.org&quot;&gt;Dave Harding&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thank-you&quot;&gt;Thank You&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you to everyone who made these pages possible, especially the
people who reviewed Bitcoin.org pull requests &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bitcoin-dot-org/bitcoin.org/pull/1044&quot;&gt;1044&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bitcoin-dot-org/bitcoin.org/pull/1009&quot;&gt;1009&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bitcoin-dot-org/bitcoin.org/pull/1007&quot;&gt;1007&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bitcoin-dot-org/bitcoin.org/pull/966&quot;&gt;966&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bitcoin-dot-org/bitcoin.org/pull/957&quot;&gt;957&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bitcoin-dot-org/bitcoin.org/pull/869&quot;&gt;869&lt;/a&gt; as well as the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcoinfoundation.org/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Foundation&lt;/a&gt; for their funding of the Bitcoin.org server
during the time these pages were written.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you enjoy the new pages.  If you see any problems, please don’t
hesitate to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bitcoin-dot-org/bitcoin.org/issues/new&quot;&gt;open an issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>//en/posts/bitcoin-core-subsite</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">//en/posts/bitcoin-core-subsite</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Repository Move</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin.org has moved our main git repository to the new
&lt;em&gt;bitcoin-dot-org&lt;/em&gt; GitHub organization:
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bitcoin-dot-org/bitcoin.org&quot;&gt;https://github.com/bitcoin-dot-org/bitcoin.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We moved to an independent organization to make clear that Bitcoin.org
and Bitcoin Core are separate projects, even though we frequently have
the pleasure of working together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing besides the repository URL has changed—Bitcoin.org will
continue to provide all of the same information and resources as it did
before.  The &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcoin.org/en/about-us#https://bitcoin.org/en/about-us#help&quot;&gt;team of contributors&lt;/a&gt; is also staying the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Existing links to the old repository (including developer git
configurations) should continue to work, but we that suggest you upgrade
them to point to the new repository at your first convenience. Git users
can who have the Bitcoin.org repository as their &lt;code&gt;upstream&lt;/code&gt; can run,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd bitcoin.org
git remote set-url upstream &#39;https://github.com/bitcoin-dot-org/bitcoin.org&#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All current &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bitcoin-dot-org/bitcoin.org/issues&quot;&gt;issues&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bitcoin-dot-org/bitcoin.org/pulls&quot;&gt;pull requests&lt;/a&gt; remain open, and any &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bitcoin-dot-org/bitcoin.org/network&quot;&gt;forks hosted
on GitHub&lt;/a&gt; shouldn’t need to be updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any problems, please &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bitcoin-dot-org/bitcoin.org/issues/new&quot;&gt;open an issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>//en/posts/repository-move</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">//en/posts/repository-move</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bitcoin.org Hard Fork Policy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Contentious hard forks are bad for Bitcoin. At the very best, a
contentious hard fork will leave people who chose the losing side of the
fork feeling disenfranchised. At the very worst, it will make bitcoins
permanently lose their value. In between are many possible outcomes, but
none of them are good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The danger of a contentious hard fork is potentially so significant
that Bitcoin.org has decided to adopt a new policy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Bitcoin.org will not promote software or services that will leave the
previous consensus because of an intentional and contentious hard fork attempt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This policy applies to full node software, such as Bitcoin Core,
software forks of Bitcoin Core, and alternative full node
implementations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also applies to wallets and services that have the ability to detect
the contentious hard fork, and which release code or make announcements
indicating that they will cease operating on the side of the previous
consensus.
It does not apply to software that cannot detect the contentious hard
fork and which continues doing whatever it would’ve done anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be clear, we encourage wallet authors and service providers to offer
their opinions on hard fork proposals, and we will not penalize anyone
for contributing to a discussion. We will only stop promoting particular
wallets and services if they plan to move their users onto a
contentious hard fork by default.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>//en/posts/hard-fork-policy</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">//en/posts/hard-fork-policy</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dev Docs: New Glossary And Search Feature</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bitcoin-dot-org/bitcoin.org/pull/793&quot;&gt;several volunteers&lt;/a&gt; and the financial sponsorship of &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcoinfoundation.org/&quot;&gt;The
Bitcoin Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, we’ve added two major new features to the
&lt;a href=&quot;/en/developer-documentation&quot;&gt;Bitcoin.org Developer Documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new &lt;a href=&quot;/en/developer-glossary&quot;&gt;glossary section&lt;/a&gt; has been added to the Bitcoin.org Developer
Documentation, and with it comes a fully-Javascript search engine that
helps you look up glossary entries, Bitcoin Core RPCs, Bitcoin BIPs,
Script-language op codes, and Bitcoin P2P protocol messages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;developer-glossary-main-page&quot;&gt;Developer glossary main page&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/free/devglossary-main-page.png&quot; alt=&quot;Developer glossary main page&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The glossary main page provides a search box and a sorted list of terms.
It uses a floating list so that it looks good on both mobiles and
desktop/laptop screens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A link is provided at the bottom of the page to allow readers to
recommend new glossary terms. (It works like the Submit New Event link
on the &lt;a href=&quot;/en/events&quot;&gt;Events page&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;glossary-entries&quot;&gt;Glossary entries&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/free/devglossary-entries.png&quot; alt=&quot;Glossary entries&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each glossary entry has its own page providing a short definition
(limited to 255 characters), one or more synonyms, zero or more “not to
be confused with” terms, and zero or more links to resources on and off
Bitcoin.org. Separate pages were used to allow search engines to link
directly to the most relevant entry, rather than forcing users to scroll
through a giant page of definitions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The glossary currently has:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;89 glossary entry pages&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;51 additional synonyms&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;222 links (all internal to Bitcoin.org or to Bitcoin Wiki, BitcoinTalk, or Bitcoin StackExchange)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each page includes links to edit it, view its history, or report an
issue about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dev-search-box&quot;&gt;Dev search box&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/free/devglossary-search-box.png&quot; alt=&quot;Glossary search box&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Javascript-powered search box is added to the following pages: &lt;a href=&quot;/en/developer-guide&quot;&gt;Dev
Guide&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/en/developer-reference&quot;&gt;Dev Reference&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/en/developer-examples&quot;&gt;Dev Examples&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/en/developer-glossary&quot;&gt;Dev Glossary&lt;/a&gt;, and individual
glossary entry pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The box allows finding the following by keyword, listed in the order
they appear in the search:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Glossary entries (Bitcoin.org)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;RPCs  (Bitcoin.org)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Op codes (Bitcoin Wiki)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;BIPs (just notable and non-withdrawn BIPs; GitHub.com BIPs repo)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bitcoin P2P protocol messages (Bitcoin.org)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The search uses &lt;a href=&quot;https://jquery.com/&quot;&gt;JQuery&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://jqueryui.com/&quot;&gt;JQuery UI&lt;/a&gt;, both MIT-licensed. Both are
loaded from the Bitcoin.org server so there’s no stats leakage when
people load them.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>//en/posts/developer-docs-glossary-and-search</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">//en/posts/developer-docs-glossary-and-search</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Site Updates In March 2015</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bitcoin-dot-org/bitcoin.org/graphs/contributors?from=2015-03-01&amp;amp;to=2015-03-31&amp;amp;type=c&quot;&gt;our
volunteers&lt;/a&gt;
and the financial sponsorship of &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcoinfoundation.org/&quot;&gt;The Bitcoin
Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, we made the following
accomplishments this month.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No more broken links:&lt;/strong&gt; all internal links on Bitcoin.org’s 834 pages
are now automatically checked by &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gjtorikian/html-proofer&quot;&gt;HTML Proofer&lt;/a&gt; through our &lt;a href=&quot;https://travis-ci.org/bitcoin-dot-org/bitcoin.org&quot;&gt;Travis
Continuous Integration (CI)&lt;/a&gt; infrastructure. We plan to enable HTML
Proofer’s HTML validation subroutine in the future to provide even
better quality assurance. Thanks to HTML Proofer author &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gjtorikian&quot;&gt;Garen
Torikian&lt;/a&gt; for writing such a great tool!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coinapult wallet&lt;/strong&gt; was briefly removed from the Bitcoin.org &lt;a href=&quot;/en/choose-your-wallet&quot;&gt;Choose Your
Wallet&lt;/a&gt; page after they suffered a security breach. After restoring
full services to their customers and assuring us that customer
deposits are safe, we re-added them.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KnC wallet&lt;/strong&gt; has been removed from the Choose Your Wallet page after
multiple issues, including an abandoned website, no new commits to
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kncgroup/bitcoin-wallet&quot;&gt;their codebase&lt;/a&gt; in several months, and reports that their iOS app
no longer worked. (In positive news, we have received reports that it
is still possible to recover funds from the wallet seed.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Translations&lt;/strong&gt; were updated thanks to translation volunteers on
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.transifex.com/projects/p/bitcoinorg/&quot;&gt;Transifex&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seven new events&lt;/strong&gt; were added. Please check the &lt;a href=&quot;/en/events&quot;&gt;Events page&lt;/a&gt; to see
whether there are any interesting Bitcoin meetups or conferences in
your area.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New pages &amp;amp; features:&lt;/strong&gt; a &lt;a href=&quot;/en/developer-documentation&quot;&gt;developer documentation&lt;/a&gt; glossary
section and Javascript-based search engine were &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bitcoin-dot-org/bitcoin.org/pull/793&quot;&gt;proposed&lt;/a&gt; but not
quite finished by the end of the month.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;site-traffic&quot;&gt;Site Traffic&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to or &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcoin.org/stats/2015-03.html&quot;&gt;website statistics&lt;/a&gt;, 4.3 million people visited the
website in March.  However, as seen in the illustration below, there was
a suspicious spike in visits that look like a possible attempt at
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Referer_spam&quot;&gt;referer spam&lt;/a&gt; (even though we don’t publish referer information).
Almost all of the suspicious traffic was directed at the Spanish, Dutch,
and French Bitcoin.org home pages, leaving statistics for the rest of
the site fairly accurate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We suspect the accurate number of unique visitors in March was around
2.0 million, roughly the same as in February.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/free/stats-2015-03.png&quot; alt=&quot;March traffic statistics graph&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notable traffic patterns this month included:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;/en/full-node&quot;&gt;Full Node Guide&lt;/a&gt; first released last month received over 8,000
page views, a surprisingly high number for a new technical document.
Hopefully this is a sign that users really want to run full nodes for
themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;/en/choose-your-wallet&quot;&gt;Choose Your Wallet page&lt;/a&gt; continues to receive over 130,000 page
views a month, as it keeps on trying to help novice users choose
their first Bitcoin wallet.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;/en/download&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Core Download page&lt;/a&gt; has just as many page views as it
did last month (75,000) when Bitcoin Core 0.10.0 was released.  If you
haven’t upgraded yet to get new features like &lt;a href=&quot;/en/developer-guide#headers-first&quot;&gt;headers-first block
sync&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/master/bip-0066.mediawiki&quot;&gt;lower vulnerability to OpenSSL code changes&lt;/a&gt;, take some
time to read the &lt;a href=&quot;/en/release/v0.10.0&quot;&gt;0.10.0 release notes&lt;/a&gt; to see what you’re missing.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thank-you-volunteers&quot;&gt;Thank You Volunteers!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Special thanks to the 19 volunteers who contributed and commented
through &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bitcoin-dot-org/bitcoin.org#how-to-participate&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; this month: anthonyc0603, arvicco, barmstrong,
Bitcoinference, borisstankovic, ConsumersResearch, dajohi, dquintela,
Firescar96, FrancisPouliot, gurnec, harding, larshesel, LinusU, louisjc,
luke-jr, muresanroland, pstratem, and saivann.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>//en/posts/site-updates-april-2015</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">//en/posts/site-updates-april-2015</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
